(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
○○初お披露目!? 重大発表!? コラボ3D LIVE!! 超生誕祭2021
ゲスト：角巻わため／桃鈴ねね
First reveal of OO!? Major announcement!? Collaboration 3D LIVE!! Super Birthday Festival 2021
Guests: Tsunomaki Watame / Momosuzu Nene
ピンポンパンポーン
Ping pong pang pong
皆さん、こんばんは！ちびあずです！
Good evening, everyone! It's Chibi Azu!
今から影ナレを読みたいと思います！
I'm going to read the announcement now!
えーっと、本日はAZKi超生誕祭に
Um, today, for the AZKi Super Birthday
お越しいただき、ありがとうございます！
thank you for coming!
開演に先立ちまして、ご来場の
Prior to the start of the show, to the visitors
お客様にお願い申し上げます。
I have a request for you.
ただいまより、公演が始まります！
The performance will now begin!
ぜひ皆様、コメントやSNSで
Please everyone, in the comments and on SNS
一緒に盛り上がってください！
let's get excited together!
ハッシュタグは、#AZKi超生誕祭2021 です！
The hashtag is #AZKi超生誕祭2021!
たくさんスクショしてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you take lots of screenshots!
じゃあ、ちびあずはおうちに帰って寝ます！
Well then, Chibi Azu is going home to sleep!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to keep seeing the same future
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
それぞれ違った
Even with our different...
心で
...hearts
走り出そう
Let's start running
Yeah!
お誕生日おめでとう!
Happy Birthday!
おめでとう!
Congratulations!
歌って行きましょう! それではまずわため!
Let's keep singing! First up, Watame!
はい!
Yes!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
It sprouted in a place where everything was pitch black
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われ
My eyes were captured by that tiny sliver of hope
ねねち!
Nene-chi!
不安に揺れる心を上手くチューニングして
I'll tune my heart, which is swaying with anxiety
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞って言いたよ
I mustered up a tiny bit of courage to say it
諦めの文字デリートして進む
Deleting the word 'give up' and moving forward
苦しい時ももう私は一人じゃないから
Because even in hard times, I'm not alone anymore
だからもっと夢追いかけたい
So I want to chase my dreams even more
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement won't stop
想像を超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that goes beyond your imagination
アクセスしてみたい
I want to try to access it
後悔なんてさせない
I won't let you have any regrets
それぞれ違った
Even with our different...
心で
...hearts
走り出そう
Let's start running
仮想の空に輝く眩しい想いは
The dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見たことのない光をリアルに届けるよ
Will deliver a never-before-seen light to the real world
いつも聞こえるエールはここにキャプチャーして
I'll capture the cheers I always hear right here
また新しい光を私たくなるよ
It makes me want to pass on a new light again
君の笑顔を保存して進む
Saving your smile and moving forward
苦しい時も見返すよ力が湧くから
Even in hard times, I'll look back at it and feel strength welling up
胸を張って夢追いかけたい
I want to chase my dreams with pride
奇跡のストーリー一緒に作ろう
Let's create a miraculous story together
終わらない夢を
In this never-ending dream
誰一人欠かせない
No one can be left out
愛が待ったこの世界
In this world where love waits
それぞれ違った
Even with our different...
心で
...hearts
彩れ
Add some color
悲しい時も寂しい時も
Even when it's sad or lonely
信じ合えるものがある
There's something we can believe in together
奏で鳴らし続けたい終わらない世界に
I want to keep playing even in an endless world
溢れ出すよ笑顔たち
Smiles will overflow
憧れの舞台立ちたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams
私らしく輝きたい
I want to shine in my own way
時になみだしてまた笑い合いたい
Sometimes crying, then wanting to laugh together again
同じ未来を見ていたい
I want to keep seeing the same future
あの夢手にしたい
I want to grasp that dream
踏み出そう奇跡の一歩を
Let's take a miraculous step forward
息を切らして夢追いかけたい
I want to chase my dreams till I'm out of breath
ワクワク止まらない
The excitement won't stop
想像を超えてく世界見せてあげる
I'll show you a world that goes beyond your imagination
アクセスしてみてよ
Try accessing it
後悔なんてここにない
There's no regret here
それぞれ違った
Even with our different...
心で
...hearts
作ろう
Let's create it
はい! 改めまして、こんあずきー!
Yes! Once again, Kon-AZKi!
こんあずきー! ありがとう!
Kon-AZKi! Thank you!
えー、今日はですね、AZKi超生誕祭2021にお越しいただき、ありがとうございます!
Um, today, thank you for coming to AZKi Super Birthday Festival 2021!
やぁ、ということで今日はですね、なんと、なんと今日、二人に来てもらいまして
Well, so today, surprisingly, surprisingly today, I have two people here with me
いてます、ちょっと挨拶をぜひお願いします!
They're here, so please introduce yourselves!
わため!
Watame!
ホロライブ四期生、角巻わためです!
From Hololive 4th Gen, I'm Tsunomaki Watame!
こんばんどどー!
Konban-dododo!
あれ? ちびあずちゃんは?
Huh? Where's Chibi-AZKi?
違います! ちょっとオープニング限定!
No! That was just for the opening!
よろしくお願いします!
Nice to meet you!
ありがとう！来てくれてありがとう！楽しむぜ！
Thank you! Thank you for coming! Let's have some fun!
そして、ねねち！
And next, Nene-chi!
はい！ホロライブ五期生、オレンジ担当の桃鈴ねねです！よろしくね！
Yes! I'm Momosuzu Nene from Hololive 5th Generation, in charge of orange! Nice to meet you!
あず先輩呼んでくれてありがとう！
AZKi-senpai, thank you for inviting me!
おめでとー！おめでとー！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
来てくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you for coming.
あのですね、今日はね、AZKiの生誕配信ということでですね、
Well, today is AZKi's birthday stream, so...
お近くで、間近で、間近で、間近でですね、
I wanted to see you from close by, very close, very close, very close...
あずおじか？
Is that Azo-ji?
あずおじ。そうです。今日はあずおじ担当です。
Azo-ji. That's right. I'm in charge of Azo-ji today.
忘れないでよ
Don't forget me,
まぁ別に関係ないけど
though it doesn't really matter.
知ってるかな
I wonder if you know,
君がくれる
that every single word
言葉一つ一つ
you give me
嬉しくなったり
makes me happy
楽しくなったり
and excited,
不思議なパワーを感じる
and I feel a mysterious power from them.
ってこと
That's how it is.
ねぇ！ひるひるひるひるひるひる一緒に
Hey! Hiru-hiru-hiru-hiru-hiru-hiru, together,
ひるひるひるひるひるひる食べよう
hiru-hiru-hiru-hiru-hiru-hiru, let's eat!
ちょっとだけ同じ気持ち
I wanted to share just a little bit
共有したくて
of the same feeling.
そう！ひるひるひるひるひるひるだけでも
Yes! Even if it's just hiru-hiru-hiru-hiru-hiru-hiru,
特別なことじゃなくても
even if it's nothing special,
いつでも君がいいんだよ
it's always you that I want.
一緒に食べよう
Let's eat together!
ハレルヤ
Hallelujah!
やったー！
Yay!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
最高！最高！
You're the best! You're the best!
ななななななななじゃなくて
It's not na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na,
ににににににににじゃなくて
it's not ni-ni-ni-ni-ni-ni-ni-ni,
ぬぬぬぬぬぬぬぬじゃなくて
it's not nu-nu-nu-nu-nu-nu-nu-nu,
ののののののののじゃなくて
it's not no-no-no-no-no-no-no-no...
うー、ねぇ！
Woo, Nene!
ねねねねねねねね!大暴走
Nene-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne! Daibousou
ねね！
Nene!
ヨイショヨイショヨイショヨイショ！
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho!
ねね！
Nene!
ヨイショヨイショヨイショヨイショ！
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho!
こんねねー！桃鈴ねねです。ホロライブ5期生
Kon-nene! I'm Momosuzu Nene. Hololive 5th gen,
オレンジ担当桃鈴ねねです。
orange member, Momosuzu Nene!
ねねちー！
Nenechi!
異世界から来ましたアイドル志望の新人VTuber！
A rookie VTuber from another world who aspires to be an idol!
まー、とにかく明るく行きましょう。ちょっとくらい空回りしたって滑ったって
Well, let's just stay cheerful. Even if I'm spinning my wheels or failing a bit,
気合で完済さ！
I'll make up for it with spirit!
どりゃあ！
Hyah!
諦めの悪さは長所だよね！
Being a sore loser is a merit, right!
ねねねねねねねね！
Nene-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne!
あんなこともあるけど
Things like that happen,
悔しいこともあるけど
and frustrating things too,
大丈夫！今日も元気に全力で
but it's okay! Today, I'll give it my all with energy again.
いつかはきっと
Someday, I'll surely be...
スーパーねねちー！
Super Nenechi!
ついてきて！ねねねねねねねね！
Follow me! Nene-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne!
ねね！
Nene!
ねねねねねねねね！
Nene-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne!
全力でいこう全開でいこう
Let's go at full power, at full throttle!
思いっきりやればなんとかなるよ
If you give it your best shot, it'll work out somehow.
ポンコツだっていいじゃん
It's okay to be a bit clumsy.
ヨイショ！
Heave-ho!
ただ駆け抜けていこうよ
Let's just keep running through!
大爆走！
Full throttle rampage!
ヨイショヨイショヨイショヨイショ！
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho!
ねね！
Nene!
ヨイショヨイショヨイショヨイショ！
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho!
大好きなお菓子揃えて準備OK！
Got all my favorite snacks ready, prep is OK!
でも朝は苦手 夜も苦手
But I'm not a morning person, nor a night person.
やっぱり睡眠って大事だよ
Sleep is really important after all!
ねねねねねねねね！
Nene-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne!
たくさんの人に愛されたい
I want to be loved by many people.
大好き、みんな！愛してるぜ！
I love you all! I love you guys!
スーパーハイパーちびねねちー！
Super-Hyper Chibi-Nenechi!
やっちゃって！ねねねねねねねね！
Go for it! Nene-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne!
ねね！
Nene!
ねねねねねねねね！
Nene-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne-ne!
全力でいこう全開でいこう
Let's go at full power, at full throttle!
誰にも負けたくないんだ
I don't want to lose to anyone.
大きな声で
With a loud voice...
ちょっとトイレ行ってくるね
I'm gonna go to the restroom for a bit!
restroom time!!!
大休憩タイム！
Big break time!
水を飲め！
Drink some water!
ななななななななじゃなくて
It's not na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na,
ににににににににじゃなくて
it's not ni-ni-ni-ni-ni-ni-ni-ni,
ぬぬぬぬぬぬぬぬじゃなくて
it's not nu-nu-nu-nu-nu-nu-nu-nu,
ののののののののじゃなくて
it's not no-no-no-no-no-no-no-no...
ただいまー！
I'm home!
最後にねねねねねねねねねねねねねねねね
Lastly, Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene
ねね！ねね！
Nene! Nene!
ねねねねねねねね
Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene
ねね！ねね！
Nene! Nene!
ねねねねねねねね
Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene-Nene
ねね！ねね！
Nene! Nene!
全力全開で今全力全開でいこう
Let's go full throttle now, going full throttle
思いっきりやればなんとかなるよ
If you give it your all, it'll work out somehow
ヨイショ！
Heave-ho!
ただ駆け抜けていこうよね
Let's just keep running through
ね！ね！ね！ね！
Ne! Ne! Ne! Ne!
ね！ね！ね！
Ne! Ne! Ne!
大爆走！
Grand stampede!
それじゃまたねね～
Well then, see you later, Nene~
またねね～
See you later, Nene~
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
ブラボー！
Bravo!
最高ー！
Amazing!
えー、はい、というわけで
Uh, yes, and so...
さてさて
Well now...
ここでね、みんな、今日はあずあず先輩のお誕生日会だから
So everyone, since today is Azu-Azu-senpai's birthday party,
ここであずあず先輩と一緒に歌っていきたいと思います！
I'd like to sing together with Azu-Azu-senpai here!
あずあず先輩！
Azu-Azu-senpai!
イエーイ！
Yay!
え、ちょっとちびあず事故が...
Eh, a little Chibi-Azu accident...
ちびあず事故が起きちゃったんですけど
A Chibi-Azu accident occurred, but...
そこもねねちのアイドル力でカバーしてもらって
Nene-chi's idol power covered for that,
めちゃくちゃ聞きたかったあの2曲を今日歌ってもらえてもう...
I've been wanting to hear those two songs so much, and hearing them today...
幸せ、幸せ、幸せです、あずきはもう
I'm happy, happy, so happy. AZKi is just...
今日もう胸がいっぱいで...
I'm so full of emotion today...
まだまだいっぱいあるから、これから！
There's still plenty more to come from here!
はい、ということで
Yes, so...
なんと今日はねねちと一緒に...
Today, I'll be together with Nene-chi...
歌います！
Singing!
歌ってみたかったんだー！
I've always wanted to sing this!
ねねちと何を歌おうかなと思って、今日あずきこの曲を選曲してきました
I was wondering what to sing with Nene-chi, so I chose this song today.
すごい良い曲です
It's a really great song.
で、これはあのね、めちゃくちゃねねちに合うと思って
And, you know, I thought this would suit Nene-chi perfectly.
ねねちって言ったら元気いっぱい、ワー！という感じで
When you think of Nene-chi, it's all energy and 'Wah!'
みんなと一緒に盛り上がれる曲になっておりますので
This is a song that everyone can get excited to,
みなさん、猫になる準備はよろしいでしょうか？
Everyone, are you ready to become cats?
よろしいでしょうか？
Are you ready?
猫になる準備をよろしくお願いします！
Please get ready to become cats!
はい、ということで二人でこの曲を歌いたいと思います
Yes, so the two of us would like to sing this song.
では一緒に行きましょう、せーの！
Then, let's go together. Ready, set...
猫ならばいける！！
If you're a cat, you can do it!!
猫になって甘やかされたい
I want to become a cat and be pampered
猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to become a cat and be loved
猫になってお昼寝させて
Let me become a cat and take a nap
起きたら100万登録いってないかな
I wonder if I'll have a million subs when I wake up
猫ならばいける
If you're a cat, you can do it
ニャ！ニャ！
Meow! Meow!
レスしたけどちゃんとおはツイしなくちゃ
I replied, but I have to do my morning tweet properly
下書きのまま三時間経って
Three hours have passed with it still in drafts
完璧な140字 推敲ミスってデリート
The perfect 140 chars, a typo in the draft and I delete it
心が折れる日曜日
A heart-breaking Sunday
休みもなしで歌い続ける そんなのへっちゃら余裕だぜ
Singing without any breaks, that's easy-peasy
みんなと一緒なら大丈夫
If I'm with everyone, it'll be okay
だから応援よろしくね 本質的に甘やかして
So please support me, pamper me to the core
マイセルフでね！
By myself, right!
でも今日はヤバイ (はいはい)
But today is crazy (yes yes)
相当にエモい (はいはい)
Extremely emotional (yes yes)
んな私もちゃんと見てほしい
I want you to see me like that too
純情な愛がほしい
I want pure love
だから猫になって甘やかされたい
So I want to become a cat and be pampered
猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to become a cat and be loved
猫になってお昼寝させて
Let me become a cat and take a nap
起きたら100万登録だにゃ
It'll be a million subscribers when I wake up, nya
猫になって輝きたいの
I want to become a cat and shine
猫になって開拓するよ
I'll blaze a trail as a cat
もっと君に伝わりますように
I hope this reaches you even more
猫ならばいける
If you're a cat, you can do it
ニャ！ニャ！
Meow! Meow!
アピールしちゃって公演で 可愛いワンちゃん見つけたよ
Showing off at the park, I found a cute doggy
撫でようとしたら吠えられた
I tried to pet it but it barked at me
やっぱ猫になりたい
I really want to be a cat
でもどうすればいい (はいはい)
But what should I do (yes yes)
猫のなりかた (はいはい)
How to become a cat (yes yes)
隠しきれない本音知ってほしい
I want you to know my true feelings I can't hide
スクール作ってほしい
I want you to build a school
だから猫になって抱きしめられたい
So I want to become a cat and be hugged
猫になってなでなでしてよ
Become a cat and pet me
猫になってエサを与えて
Become a cat and feed me
山盛りチュールはよろしくね
Please give me a heap of Churu
猫になって恋してたいの
I want to become a cat and be in love
猫になって笑いあうのよ
Become a cat and laugh together
もっとみんな猫になろうよ
Let's all become cats more
ニャ！ニャ！
Meow! Meow!
ほんとやばい
Truly awful
起きたら12時
When I woke up, it was noon
LINEめちゃ来てる
I have tons of LINE messages
でもしょうがない
But it can't be helped
逆に二度寝しましょ
On the contrary, let's take a second nap
だから猫になって甘やかされたい
So I want to become a cat and be pampered
猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to become a cat and be loved
猫になってお昼寝させて
Let me become a cat and take a nap
起きたら100万登録だ
When I wake up, I'll have a million subscribers
猫になって輝きたいよ
I want to become a cat and shine
猫になって開拓するよ
I'll become a cat and pioneer
もっと君に伝わりますように
So that it reaches you even more
もっともっと！
More and more!
猫になって甘やかされたい ずっと
I want to become a cat and be pampered forever
猫になって抱きしめられたい もっと
I want to become a cat and be hugged even more
猫になって恋してたの
I was in love as a cat
猫になって笑い合おうよ
Let's become cats and laugh together
もっとみんな猫になっちゃおうよ
Let's everyone become cats more
猫ならいける
If it's a cat, it'll work
ねねとならいける
With Nene, it'll work
どこまでもついていくよ！
I'll follow you anywhere!
にゃーーー！
Nyaaa!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました！
わためー！ねねちー！
Watame! Nenechi!
わためー！今日は羊から猫になって...
Watame! Today you went from a sheep to a cat...
今日だけ猫ちゃん
Just for today, a kitty cat
ねねちとこの曲を歌ったら絶対楽しいと思って
I thought it would definitely be fun to sing this song with Nenechi
今日、今実際にめっちゃ楽しかった！
It was actually really fun today, just now!
コメントもみんな、ちょうどね、スタンプに「にゃ」っていうのがあるんですよ
In the comments too, everyone, just right there, there's a 'nya' stamp
それでみんな猫になってもらいました
So I had everyone become cats
ありがとう！
Thank you!
可愛かった！めっちゃ楽しかった！
It was cute! It was so much fun!
わためも合いの手ありがとう！
Watame, thanks for the backing calls too!
「にゃ」しか言ってないんだけど
I only said 'nya' though
「めぇ」じゃないの
It's not 'mee'?
にゃ！
Nya!
ということでですね、次はわためのソロパート！
And so, next is Watame's solo part!
楽しみ！頑張って！
Can't wait! Good luck!
頑張る！
I'll do my best!
ねねおじとあずおじするんだ。待ってるからな。
Nene-oji and Azu-oji will be watching. I'll be waiting.
あ、見られる側って、こういう気持ちだったんだ
Ah, being the one watched... this is how it feels
頑張って！
Good luck!
脇ストリームじゃない！
It's not a 'Waki Stream'!
ではここからはソロですね。頑張りたいと思います！
Well, from here it's solo. I'm going to do my best!
猫から、この曲になります。
From a cat, I'll transform into this song.
「怪物」！
Monster!
素晴らしい世界に今日も乾杯 街に飛び交う笑い声も
A toast to this wonderful world again today
Even the laughter flying around the city
見て見ぬふりしてるだけの作りもんさ 気が触れそうだ
Is just a fabrication that everyone's pretending not to see
I feel like I'm losing my mind
くらくらするほどの良い匂いが ツンと刺した鼻の奥
A scent so strong it makes me dizzy
Stung deep in the back of my nose
目を覚ます本能のまま 今日は誰の番だ この世界で
Awakening just as my instincts dictate
Whose turn is it today in this world?
何ができるのか
What can I do?
僕には何ができるのか
What is it that I can do?
ただその真っ黒な目から 涙こぼれ落ちないように
Just so that tears don't spill
From those pitch-black eyes
ああ願う未来に何度でもずっと
Ah, to the future I wish for, over and over, forever
食らいつくこの間違いだらけの世界の中君には笑ってほしいから
I'll cling to it, in this error-filled world
Because I want you to be smiling
もう誰も傷つけない
I won't let anyone be hurt anymore
強く強くなりたいんだよ 僕が僕でいられるように
I want to become strong, so strong
So that I can remain as myself
素晴らしい世界は今日も安泰 街に渦巻く悪い話も
The wonderful world is peaceful again today
Even the bad stories swirling through the city
知らない知らないふりして目を逸らした 正気の沙汰じゃないな
I pretended not to know and looked away
It's not the behavior of someone sane
真面目に着飾った行進 鳴らす足音が弾む
A march dressed up in seriousness
The sound of footsteps ringing out is bouncy
行き先は消えない消えない 味が染み付いている 裏側の世界
The destination won't disappear
The taste is soaked in, the world on the other side
清く正しく生きること 誰も悲しませずに生きること
Living purely and correctly
Living without making anyone sad
はみ出さずに真っ直ぐに生きること それが間違わないで生きること
Living straight without stepping out of line
That is what it means to live without mistakes
ありのままでいることが正義か
Is staying as you are a form of justice?
騙し騙し生きるのは正義か
Is living by deceiving a form of justice?
僕のあるべき姿とはなんだ
What is the way I ought to be?
本当の僕は何者なんだ 教えてくれ
Who am I really? Tell me
教えてくれよ
Tell me.
今日も答えのない世界の中で
In this world with no answers today either,
願ってるんだよ 不器用だけれど
I'm making a wish, clumsy as I am.
いつまでも君とただ笑っていたいから
Because I want to just keep smiling with you forever.
ああ、跳ねる心臓が体揺らし
Ah, my bounding heart shakes my body,
叫ぶんだよ 今こそ動き出せ
and I scream, "Now is the time to start moving!"
ああ、弱い自分を何度でもずっと
Ah, no matter how many times, I'll always
食らい尽くすこの間違いだらけの
devour my weak self. In this
世界の中 君には笑ってほしいから
world full of mistakes, I want you to be smiling.
もう誰も泣かないよ
No one will cry anymore.
強く、強くなりたいんだよ
I want to become strong, stronger.
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can remain being myself.
ただ君を守るそのために
Simply for the sake of protecting you,
走れ、走れ、走るんだよ
run, run, keep on running!
僕の中の僕を超え
Surpass the self within me!
盛り上がってください！
Please get excited!
いくぞー！
Here we go!
まだまだー！
Not done yet!
あ、またやっちゃった
Ah, I did it again.
隠してたわけじゃないの
It's not that I was hiding it.
きっとただ言ってないだけ
I probably just didn't say it.
だって恥ずかしいんだもん
Because it's embarrassing!
愛昧ショコラーテ
Ai-mai Chocolate.
歌ったー！
I'm singing it!
いってみよう！
Let's go!
意外と寂しん坊
Unexpectedly lonely-hearted,
意外と甘えん坊
Unexpectedly clingy,
意外と慌てん坊
Unexpectedly scatterbrained,
意外と照れ屋
Unexpectedly shy.
丸い飛行機雲
A round vapor trail,
飛び出したカップケーキ
a cupcake that popped out,
散開のコンディショナー
scattered conditioner,
アンバランス
unbalance.
ふわふわ 浮かぶ夢見心地
Fluffy and floating, a dreamy feeling.
ひとつひとつ数えて
Counting them one by one,
おやすみなさい
good night.
密かに芽生えた この気持ち
These feelings that secretly sprouted,
真っ直ぐ見つめないで
don't look straight at them.
なんだったっけ？
What was it?
言葉にしちゃった時
When I put it into words,
そうじゃない 照れちゃうだけ
that's not it, I'm just getting shy.
本当の本当は隠したい
In truth, I really want to hide it.
じゃない もっとそうじゃないのになあ
No, it's not even like that, though.
アイマイマインじゃない
It's not "Ai Mai Mine,"
この気持ちは間違いじゃない
these feelings are not a mistake.
指切りげんまん
Pinky promise.
かなりドジっ子で
Quite a klutz,
優柔不断でも
and even if I'm indecisive,
絶対に毎日
every single day,
会いに来てくれるよね
you'll come to see me, right?
いくぞー！
Here we go!
本来臆病で
Originally cowardly,
案外泣き虫
and surprisingly a crybaby,
全然変わらずに
without changing at all,
隣に君ばかり
it's always you by my side.
弊社 君がいないとガッカリしちゃう
At my place, I'd be disappointed without you.
本当の本当にしょんぼりしちゃうわ
I'd really, truly feel downcast.
会いたくなっちゃうなあ
I'll end up wanting to see you.
後悔ばっかじゃ
If it's just regrets,
この心も勇気出しちゃえ
let this heart muster some courage too.
この指止まれ
Join me!
止まらない！
Can't stop!
AZKiちゃん 本当に誕生日おめでとう！
AZKi-chan, a truly happy birthday to you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
Neneちゃんも！
And Nene-chan too!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
一緒にこの舞台に立ててること
That we are able to stand on this stage together...
すごくすごく嬉しいです！
...makes me so, so happy!
一緒に歌いたかったんだ！
I really wanted to sing together!
見てくれてる皆様 ありがとう！
Thank you to everyone watching!
...良いところ気付かれたり
...having you notice my good points.
寂しさごと包まれたり
...being wrapped up along with my loneliness.
いつまでも笑い合ったり
...laughing together forever.
たまにはちょっとケンカをしたり
...sometimes having little fights.
ずっとずっとそばにいてほしい
I want you to be by my side forever and ever.
約束だぞ！
That's a promise!
言っちゃった...
I said it...
もしかしたら運命かも
Maybe it's fate.
赤い糸が見えちゃうかも
Maybe I can see the red thread.
ホントのホントはバレてるのかも
Maybe you've actually known all along.
目、逸らさないかも
I might not look away.
曖昧なんてない
There's no ambiguity.
さぁ、さぁ、私を見てて
Come on, come on, keep looking at me.
指切り、た！
Pinky swear!
可愛いー！
So cute!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
2曲ほど歌わせていただきました！
I just performed two songs!
えー、ここで...
Um, now...
あの曲を。
That song.
ついに。
Finally.
AZKiちゃんと一緒に...
Together with AZKi-chan...
歌いたいと思います！AZKiちゃん！
I'd like to sing! AZKi-chan!
何を歌ってくれるんだー？
What are we going to sing?
ちょっと、その前に。
Wait, before that.
水飲んで。
Drink some water.
休憩タイム。
Break time.
いや、『Ai Mai Chocolate』めっちゃ聴きたかったの。
Man, I really wanted to hear 'Ai Mai Chocolate'.
実はあの、AZKiの『音楽を止めるな』シリーズの...
Actually, in AZKi's 'Don't Stop the Music' series...
ライブのパートがあったんですけど。
There was a live performance part.
そこでも、実は歌わせてもらったりもしていて。
I actually got to sing it there too.
もう、これ本人の歌をね。
Now, I finally get to hear the original's singing.
聴きたくて、もうここ来たまである、本当に。
I came here just because I wanted to hear it, seriously.
緊張だよ、AZKiちゃんの歌大好きだからさ。
I'm so nervous, because I love your singing, AZKi-chan.
いや、本当に歌ってくれてありがとう。
No, thank you so much for singing it.
袖で『オウオウ』するのが夢だったの。
It was a dream of mine to do the 'Woah-woah' from the sidelines.
楽しかった！楽しかった！
It was so fun! It was fun!
というわけで、次の曲なんですけど。
And so, about the next song...
あの曲を歌います。
We'll be singing that song.
実は、わためが歌ってくれてて、いろんな場所で。
Actually, Watame has been singing it in various places.
まさか、あの曲が...
No way, that song...
あの曲、来てしまうのか。
Is that song coming?
すごいね、AZKiもめっちゃ嬉しくて。
It's amazing, AZKi is also very happy.
わための歌枠、その中で。
During Watame's singing stream.
記念日に、最初の方にめっちゃ歌ってくれたよね。
You sang it a lot on anniversaries and right at the start.
この曲好きで。
I love this song.
本当に、なんかそれを聞きつけて...
Really, hearing about that...
なんていい子なんだ。
I thought, 'What a good girl she is'.
なんで、こんな歌ってくれるんだろうと思って。
I wondered why she would sing it so much.
わためにずっとお近づきになりたくて。
I've wanted to get closer to Watame for a while.
今日はですね、なんと二人で...
Today, believe it or not, the two of us...
その曲を歌いたいと思います！
Are going to sing that song!
ということで、一緒にタイトルコール。
So, let's do the title call together.
聞いてください。せーの！
Please listen. One, two!
『いのち』
'Life'
息をしている
I am breathing.
君は生きている
You are living.
当然のこと　誰も疑わないの
It's obvious, no one doubts it.
息をしている
I am breathing.
ように見えている
Or so it seems.
生の裏側　私にとっての何か
The other side of life, something meant for me.
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heart is thumping.
叩かれても腐らずに
Without rotting even if I'm beaten down.
ここで歌うよ　もうひとつ　いのちを
I'll sing here, for another life.
最後まで私のこと　覚えててくれるの？
Will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの　わかってよ　わかってよ
I feel like I'm about to disappear, please understand, please understand.
ねぇ本当のことなの　愛おしさは違うでしょ
Hey, it's the truth, the way we love is different, isn't it?
君が忘れちゃったら　私はいなくなるの
If you forget me, I'll cease to exist.
いのちのような　夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream that's like a life.
またね　バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye.
息をしている
I am breathing.
だから生きている
Therefore, I am living.
自己証明を欲しがって　欲しがっている
Wanting, wanting proof of my existence.
音が止まって
The sound stops
動けなくなって
And I'm unable to move
そんな私を君は笑ってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll smile at me like that
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heart is thumping
嫌われても腐らずに
Without rotting even if I'm hated
ここで歌うよ
I'll sing here
気分次第
Depending on my mood
命
Life
最後まで私のこと
Will you keep watching over me
見届けてくれるぞ
Until the very end?
避けきれそうにないの
It doesn't seem like I can avoid it
分かってよ 分かってよ ねぇ
Understand me, understand me, hey
声が聞こえるんだ
I can hear a voice
後ろから涙が出ちゃいそう
It feels like tears will come from behind
君が忘れちゃったら
If you forget
私はいなくなるの
I will disappear
命のような夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life
またねバイバイ
See you again, bye-bye
バイバイなんて言わないで！
Don't say things like bye-bye!
叫んだあの日のことを
That day when I screamed
軽く弄らないでやめて
Don't tease me about it, stop it
そう願い生きる糧になるから
Because wishing so will become my food for living
大丈夫 ずっと私は歌い続けるから
It's okay, I will continue to sing forever
最後まで私は生きてるか分からないけど
I don't know if I'll be alive until the end
君がくれた言葉は
But the words you gave me
確かに残ってる
Are certainly still here
最後まで私のこと
Will you remember me
覚えていてくれるぞ
Until the very end?
必死に生きるんだろう
I'll live desperately, I guess
分かんない 分かんないよね
I don't know, you don't know either, right?
痛いくらい気持ちがシンクロする時もあるけど
There are times when our feelings sync to a painful degree
君が忘れちゃったら
If you forget
私はいなくなるの
I will disappear
命のような夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream like life
またねバイバイ
See you again, bye-bye
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
わためぇと一緒に歌ってくれてありがとう！
Thank you for singing with Watame!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
良かったー！
That was great!
ねねちょ、芽吹いた？命。
Nene-cho, did it sprout? 'Life'.
整っちゃった？
Did you feel refreshed?
感情になってたね。
You were full of emotion.
感情…ねね生まれました。命生まれました。
Emotion... Nene was born. Life was born.
生誕、爆誕。
Birth, explosion.
そう爆誕しました。
Yes, I exploded into birth.
はい、ということで、わためと一緒に「命」を歌いました。
Yes, so, I sang "Inochi" together with Watame.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
やー、もう結構もう胸がいっぱいなんですけど。
Wow, my heart is already quite full.
分かる。
I understand.
もうね、今日このライブも、もうね、リハーサルした時からもう結構もう、何だろう、もう今日ありがとうっていう気持ちでいっぱい。
You know, even with today's live, ever since the rehearsal, I've been just, what can I say, full of "thank you" feelings.
いえいえ。
No, no.
二人がこうやって来てくれて、今日一緒に歌ってくれて、AZKiはもう胸がいっぱいです。ありがとうございます。
Having you two come here like this and sing with me today, AZKi's heart is full. Thank you very much.
こちらこそ！ありがとうございます！
Likewise! Thank you very much!
やー、もう帰ろうかな？
Well, maybe I'll head home now?
ダメだよ！
No way!
みんな聞きたいですよね？
Everyone wants to hear more, right?
帰ろうかなー。
Maybe I'll go home.
次がまだあるのにおー！
Even though there's still more to come!
ねねソロ、わためソロも、今日もう満腹、満腹。
Nene's solo, Watame's solo, I'm already full, full for today.
ダメダメダメダメ。
No, no, no, no.
じゃあ強制的に、じゃあ次はAZKiちゃんのソロパートがあります！
Then by force, next up is AZKi-chan's solo part!
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
はい、心を込めて歌わせていただきます。
Yes, I will sing with all my heart.
楽しみにしてるよ！聴かせてもらいます！
We're looking forward to it! We'll be listening!
バイバイバイバイ！
Bye-bye, bye-bye!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はい、ということで、ここからはソロパートね、それぞれねねちとわために歌ってもらったので、ここはAZKiのソロパートを最後に歌ってですね、
Yes, so, from here is the solo part; since I had Nene-chi and Watame sing their respective parts, I'll sing AZKi's solo part at the end,
やっていきたいと思います。
and I'd like to get started.
それでは聴いてください。この曲から行きます。リアルメランコリー。
Then please listen. I'll start with this song. Real Melancholy.
答え教えてよ リアルメランコリー
Tell me the answer, Real Melancholy
みんなも一緒に！
Everyone together!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
イェーイ! ありがとう!
Yeah! Thank you!
身体と感情が 交差する
My body and emotions intersect
ただ 地 自分は何？
Just what am I myself?
実と虚をつないで 交差する
Connecting truth and falsehood, intersecting
世界は一つじゃない
The world is not just one
セレクトパネル スムーズに増えていく
Select panels increasing smoothly
思う通り正義を振りかざして首を絞める
Brandishing justice as I please, strangling myself
私の生きる世界は自分の手で選ばせてよ
Let me choose the world I live in with my own hands
真夜中のメランコリー 生まれ変わるアイデンティティ
Midnight melancholy, a reborn identity
この身がこの辺が 痛いよ
This body, this part here, it hurts
上辺だけの泣きストーリー 収束してく可愛いフェイス
A superficial crying story, a converging cute face
私は 私は 誰かにとって変わるの
I, I, will change for someone
理想と現実が 交差する
Ideal and reality intersect
ただ 地 私は何？
Just what am I?
再生回数が 落ちていく
View counts are falling
世界はどこも同じだ
The world is the same everywhere
キャラ属性カテゴリライズ されていく
Being categorized by character attributes
誰かに決めつけられたような流行はやだな
I hate trends that feel like they were decided by someone else
私のやりたいことは自分の手で決めさせてよ
Let me decide what I want to do with my own hands
真夜中のメランコリー 生まれ変わるアイデンティティ
Midnight melancholy, a reborn identity
この身がこの辺が 痛いよ
This body, this part here, it hurts
嘘じゃないこの思い 偽りないこの思い
These feelings aren't a lie, these feelings aren't false
私は 私は 誰かにとって変わるの
I, I, will change for someone
流行りと好き どっちも欲しい
Both trends and things I like, I want both
矛盾の自問自答 繰り返してく
Repeating a contradictory internal dialogue
何番目のコピーじゃないの 永遠の夜を超えてく
I'm not some numbered copy, I'm crossing the eternal night
未知なる世界へ
To an unknown world
一人目の手を繋いで
Holding hands with the first person
真夜中のメランコリー 生まれ変わるアイデンティティ
Midnight melancholy, a reborn identity
だけどね 私は 一人じゃない
But you know, I'm not alone
どこかの世界の君へ 私と似てる気持ちの君へ
To you somewhere in the world, to you with feelings similar to mine
エールを送るよ 私のために
I'll send you a cheer, for myself
真夜中のメランコリー 生まれ変わるアイデンティティ
Midnight melancholy, a reborn identity
この身がこの辺が 痛いけど
This body, this part here, it hurts, but...
どこかの世界の君へ 私と似てる君へ
To you somewhere in the world, to you who are like me
エールを送るよ 君と私のために
I'll send you a cheer, for you and for me
ありがとうございましたー!
Thank you very much!
愛が言葉を 見失ってる
Love is losing its words
空が涙を 降らせていたんだ
The sky was making tears fall
誰のために 何のために
For whom, for what purpose?
これが運命だというの
Do you call this fate?
嘘が街を 包み込んでいる
Lies are enveloping the city
鳥が飛べずに 声を上げていた
Birds were crying out, unable to fly
たった一つの 存在を灯す
Lighting up a single existence
この場所で君を待ってる
I'm waiting for you at this place
世界はとても苦しそうでした
The world seemed to be in great pain
私に何ができるというの?
What can I possibly do?
歌うことが正しいかなんて
Whether singing is the right thing or not...
今も答えは見つからないけど
I still haven't found the answer, but...
確かなのは君がいたから...
What's certain is that because you were here...
私はここにいるの
I am here
何回 何十回だって
Again and again, dozens of times
君と出会うから
Because I'll meet you
夜が明けていく 光...
The night is breaking, light...
…が降り注ぎ
...pour down upon us
喜び悲しみを抱え前を向く
Carrying joy and sorrow, I look forward
君と生きる　ここで　この場所で
Living with you, right here in this place
それが私の世界だ
That is my world
その一秒一瞬が煌めく
That single second, that instant sparkles
過去が道を壊したとしても
Even if the past destroyed the path
夢が街を食らい尽くそうとしても
Even if dreams were to devour the city
大丈夫だから　そばにいるよ
It's okay, because I'm by your side
君に笑って欲しいんだ
I want you to smile
生まれた意味を探しているの
I'm searching for the meaning of being born
鼓動のまま　ただ走り続けていく
Following my heartbeat, I just keep on running
今を知って　明日を拓いた
Knowing the present, I opened up tomorrow
心が叫びたがってる
My heart wants to scream out
タイムマシンに乗ってさ　別の未来を選べたなら
If I could ride a time machine and choose a different future
君のいない世界を創造する？　そんな世界は想像できない
Would I create a world without you? I can't imagine such a world
「君に届きますように…」
"May it reach you..."
この声が　この歌が　何回何十回だって君を選ぶから
This voice, this song, no matter how many times, will choose you
夜が滲んでいく　地平の彼方へ
The night begins to blur towards the horizon
響く呼吸の音　確かに感じた
The sound of resounding breath, I definitely felt it
始めよう　君との未来を
Let's begin our future together
繋いだ手を離さないで
Don't let go of my hand
大きな声で名前を呼んで
Call my name in a loud voice
奇跡を駆け抜けて
Racing through miracles
どこまでも行けるよ
We can go anywhere
ここからもう一度　君と私で始めよう
From here, once more, let's start over, you and me
無限の中に生まれる物語を　君と歩いていく
I'll walk with you through the story born within infinity
この世界が悲しみに溢れたとしても
Even if this world is overflowing with sadness
私は歌を歌い続けていく
I will continue to sing my songs
君と生きる　ここで　この場所で
Living with you, right here in this place
それが私の世界だ
That is my world
その一秒一瞬が煌めく
That single second, that instant sparkles
傷つき涙を流す君が　幸せだと思える世界になりますように
May the world become a place where you, hurt and crying, can feel happy
願いを込める歌
A song filled with my wishes
最高だ！AZKi先輩！
That was awesome! AZKi-senpai!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
輝いてたよ！最高！
You were shining! Amazing!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はい、ということで、AZKiソロパートは「リアルメランコリー」、「In this World」の2曲をお届けいたしました！
Alright, so for AZKi's solo part, I performed two songs: "Real Melancholy" and "In this World"!
そしてそして！皆さん見てください、新しい...
And also, and also! Everyone, please look! This is a new...
なんだそれ！？
What is that!?
これですね、AZKiのセカンド衣装なんですけれども、こうちょっとね、新衣装になってからちょっとそれに...
This is AZKi's second costume. Since getting my new outfit, I wanted something to go with it...
それに合わせて、なんと新しくしてもらいました！
And I had this made to match it!
最高！
Awesome!
ありがとう、ありがとう！
Thank you, thank you!
どうですか？どうですか？
How is it? How is it?
あ、すごい、すごい！
Oh, wow! It's amazing!
すごい衣装、そう、あの、ありがとうございます。
An amazing costume, yes... um, thank you very much.
ねねちありがとう！
Thanks, Nenechi!
いい足！
Nice legs!
わためぇありがとう！
Thanks, Watame!
はい、ということでね、あのね、パパにね、ちゃんとこうちょっとまたお仕立て綺麗にしてもらいました。
Yes, so, my "Papa" tailored this beautifully for me again.
やべぇ！
Insane!
ということで、皆さんね、ちょっとね、今日まるまるお披露目っていうね、あの、サムネにあったんですけれども...
So, as mentioned in the thumbnail about today being a "Full Reveal"...
「ちびあず」と思いきや、なんとこちらセカンド衣装...
You might have expected "Chibi Azu," but it was actually a reveal for this second costume...
新しいセカンド衣装のお披露目でした！
The reveal of my new second costume!
グッジョブ、グッジョブ、グッジョブ！
Good job, good job, good job!
みんなスクショ撮ったほうがいいんじゃないの？
Shouldn't everyone be taking screenshots?
バシバシ、バシバシ！
Snap, snap, snap!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
こういう気持ちになるんだ。
So this is how it feels.
お客さん見てるよ！
The audience is watching!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
はい、ということで、えっとですね、実はまだお知らせがなんと...
Alright, and so, the truth is, I still have...
2つ！
Two announcements!
あります！
I have some!
なんだってー！？
What is it?!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
では、一つ目の画像おねがいしまーす、ドン！
Now, for the first image, please... Ta-da!
ドン！
Ta-da!
はい、本日より、AZKiの生誕記念グッズ2021の受注開始いたします！
Yes, starting today, orders for AZKi Birthday Commemorative Goods 2021 are now open!
最高！イエーイ！
Awesome! Yay!
なんと、そう、あのね、新しい衣装になってからグッズがなんと初めてなんですけれども、
Amazingly, yes, you know, this is actually the first set of goods since I got my new costume.
今回ですね、三つあります。
There are three items this time.
一つ目は、島田先生描き下ろしのB2タペストリー！
First is a B2 tapestry illustrated by Shimada-sensei!
欲しい！
I want it!
キラキラ、キラキラのアイドルなAZKiをぜひおうちに飾ってください。
Please decorate your home with this sparkly, idol-like AZKi.
そしてですね、次、
And next,
二つ目、二宮ニノ先生描き下ろしのちびAZラバーキーホルダーセットです！
second is the Chibi AZ rubber keychain set illustrated by Ninomiya Nino-sensei!
なんと四種類入っておりますよ！
It contains four different types!
お得！
What a deal!
はい、ちびAZは早速ね、グッズになりました。
Yes, Chibi AZ has already become a piece of merchandise.
早い、今日初めてこう動いたんですけど、
That was fast, since she just started moving today.
ありがとうございます。えっと、こちらもよろしくお願いします。
Thank you. Please check this out too.
そして最後に、3rd衣装のアクリルスタンドです！
And finally, an acrylic stand featuring my 3rd costume!
欲しい！
I want it!
買うしかない！
I have to buy it!
こちらですね、全てこのあと21時からAZKiオフィシャルストアにて受注販売開始いたします。
All of these will be available for order starting at 21:00 today at the AZKi Official Store.
8月3日までの1ヶ月の期間限定になるので、ぜひこの機会に買ってください！
They're only available for a limited time of one month until August 3rd, so please don't miss this chance!
急げ！
Hurry up!
今すぐ買え！
Buy it now!
ありがとう、急げということで。
Thank you, "hurry up" indeed.
さて、もう一つのお知らせなんですけれども、
Now, for another announcement,
重大発表、画像おねがいします、ドン！
a major announcement. Image, please... Ta-da!
おっ！わっ！
Oh! Whoa!
延期になっておりました、AZKi 8th LIVE "Rewind & Reunion"の開催が、9月12日、池袋harevutaiに決まりました！
The postponed AZKi 8th LIVE "Rewind & Reunion" is now scheduled for September 12th at Ikebukuro harevutai!
すごい！おめでとう！
Amazing! Congratulations!
待ってたよ！
We've been waiting!
ついに来たー！
It's finally here!
今回ですね、9月12日に開催が決まりました。
The date is set for September 12th.
まだね、ちょっとまだまだ情勢がね、わからないところなんですけど、
The situation is still a bit uncertain, but...
みんなとやっと再会できる場所としてこの日を作りました。
I set this day aside as a place where I can finally reunite with everyone.
2019年の12月29日に、アズリンネで止まってしまった時計をですね、
The clock that stopped at "AZRinne" on December 29th, 2019...
みんなと一緒に、もう一度動かし始められたらって思っていますので、
I hope we can start moving it forward together once again.
ぜひぜひ来てくれたら嬉しいです。
So I'd be very happy if you could come.
チケットなどの詳細は、来月です、お知らせできると思うので、
Details about tickets and more will be announced next month.
お楽しみに！ということで、お知らせ二つでした！
So look forward to it! That's it for the two announcements!
絶対行くよ！
I'm definitely going!
ありがとう。じゃあ二人、カモンカモン！
Thank you. Now, you two, come on over!
行っちゃうよー！
Here we come!
飛んできた。ありがとう。
They flew over. Thank you.
おーいいね、この姿も好き。
Oh, nice. I like this look too.
お触りいいんですか？
Can we touch you?
ここだよ、なんだここ、
Right here. What's going on?
お触り、可愛すぎるここ。
Touching... this is too cute.
いいんですか？どこ触ってんの。
Is it okay? Where are you touching?
お触り、最高。どこ触ってんですか。
Touching, it's the best. Where are you touching?!
本物だ。
They're the real deal.
怒られちゃう。スーハースーハーしてる。
I'll get in trouble. They're sniffing me.
はい、ということでね、今日はもう盛りだくさんの、すごいおじさんが二人いますけど、
Alright, well, we've had a packed schedule today, with these two creepy guys here...
おじさん！？
Creepy guys?!
はい、盛りだくさんの、ねねちに、ねねちね、ねねち！
Yes, a lot happened with Nenechi, Nenechi, Nenechi!
今浴びてる。
I'm soaking it in right now.
ねねのソロパート、三人で最初に"Shiny Smily Story"歌って、ねねちのソロパート、そしてねねちと一緒に"猫ならばいける"歌ったあと、
Nene's solo part, we all sang "Shiny Smily Story" together first, then Nenechi's solo part, and we sang "Neko Naraba Ikeru" with Nenechi,
わためのソロパート、"いのち"を歌いましたね。
then Watame's solo part, we sang "Inochi."
イエーイ！
Yay!
そしてAZKiのソロパートで"となりまち"、もう三人ね、ね、三人ね、ここに集まったんだから、
And for AZKi's solo part, I sang "Tonari Machi." Since the three of us are all gathered here now...
最後の曲、三人で、
the final song, with the three of us...
いいんですか？歌っちゃいましょうか。
Is it okay? Should we sing it?
イエーイ！
Yay!
あ、ちょっとその前に、ちょっと着替えます。
Ah, wait, before that, let me change.
どうやって？
How?
お、え、すげー！最高！最高すぎる！
Oh, whoa, amazing! Awesome! Too awesome!
はい、着替えてまいりました。はい、今日はね、本当に改めてこんなに可愛い可愛いね、可愛いね可愛いね。
Alright, I'm changed. Today, really, once again, having such cute guests... cute, cute, cute.
イエーイ！
Yay!
二人と一緒に生誕ライブができてめちゃくちゃ幸せな本当にお誕生日になりました。ありがとう二人とも。
Having this birthday live with both of you has made it a truly happy birthday. Thank you both.
いやこうやってね、なんか、初めの誕生日の時はこんな風になんかゲスト呼んだりとか、なんかする未来が全然なんかこう予想もしてなかったので、
You know, at my first birthday, I never even imagined a future where I'd be able to invite guests like this,
今日こうやって二人と一緒にライブできて嬉しいです。これからも、エモ、エモが重すぎて...
so I'm so happy to be able to do this live with both of you today. From now on... the emotions are just too heavy...
こうやってね、本当に、なんか一緒に歌える日が来るなんてという気持ちでいっぱいなので、これからもまた一緒に歌ってください！
My heart is so full just thinking that the day would come when we could sing together like this, so please sing with me again in the future!
こちらこそ！
Likewise!
もちろん！
Of course!
よろしくお願いします！
Please join us!
ぜひお願いします！
Yes, please!
私もすごい…45度以上…
I'm also... over 45 degrees...
お願いします、お願いします。
Please, thank you.
ということで、これからもね、なんかそれぞれがね、
And so, from now on as well, since each of us
歌、オリジナル曲とか出してて頑張っているので、AZKiも頑張っていきたいと思います。
is working hard on our songs and original music, AZKi wants to keep doing her best too.
それでは、最後の曲、いきますか？
Well then, shall we move on to the last song?
はい！いきましょう！
Yes! Let's go!
では3人でタイトルコールしましょう。
Then let's do the title call, the three of us.
聞いてください。せーの！
Please listen. One, two!
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let the freshly born excitement resound
最高の時間　最高の仲間と
The best time, with the best of friends
キラメキに乗って
Ride on the sparkle
イェーイ！
Yeah!
最後まで盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's keep the energy high until the end!
覚えてるかな　最初の歌
Do you remember the first song?
私声が震えていた
My voice was trembling
あの日から続く未来は
The future that continues from that day
みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
Is the "today" I grasped with everyone
もっと　もっと　もっと　もっと　加速するハート
More, more, more, more, my heart accelerates
一緒に行こう　どこまでも
Let's go together, no matter how far
Are you ready? 準備はオッケー？
Are you ready? Is your preparation okay?
開け夢の扉を
Open the door to your dreams
1, 2, 3 キラメキライダー
1, 2, 3 Kirameki Rider
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let the freshly born excitement resound
最高の時間　最高の仲間と
The best time, with the best of friends
ここにいるよ　見つけてくれたから
I'm here, because you found me
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ　みんなで歌おう
I came here because I wanted to see you, let's all sing together
終わらないメロディ
An unending melody
キラメキに乗って
Ride on the sparkle
イェーイ！
Yeah!
届いてるかな　私の声
Is my voice reaching you?
届けたいのは君に笑顔
What I want to deliver is a smile to you
理想の向こう側に駆け出して
Running towards the other side of my ideals
みんなと泣き笑い重ね
Sharing tears and laughter with everyone
ギュッと　ギュッと　ギュッと　ギュッと　強く抱きしめて
Tightly, tightly, tightly, tightly, hold on tight
一緒に行こう　どこまでも
Let's go together, no matter how far
Are you ready? 準備はオッケー？
Are you ready? Is your preparation okay?
進め希望の道を
Move forward on the path of hope
1, 2, 3 キラメキライダー
1, 2, 3 Kirameki Rider
好きな気持ちカラフルに奏でたいんだ
I want to play my feelings of love colorfully
最高の場所　最高の仲間と
The best place, with the best of friends
ここにいるよ　幻なんかじゃない
I'm here, it's not a phantom
君の心が幸せに染まるように
So that your heart will be colored with happiness
重ねてくハーモニー
Piling up harmonies
キラメキに乗って
Ride on the sparkle
歌い続けたいんだ　踊り続けたいな
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing
そんな願いやワガママもいいでしょ？
Is such a wish or selfishness okay?
だって楽しすぎて　もう止まらない
Because it's so fun, I can't stop anymore
輝くステージでもっともっと
Even more on the shining stage
お願い！
Please!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
嬉しい　楽しい　愛しいだけじゃ語れない
I can't talk about it just being happy, fun, or dear
今も今も悩みはあるけど
Even now, even now, I have worries
ここにいるよ　私ここにいるよ
I'm here, I am right here
君と同じ世界を見つめて
Looking at the same world as you
行くよ！　キラメキライダー
Here we go! Kirameki Rider
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let the freshly born excitement resound
最高の時間　最高の仲間と
The best time, with the best of friends
ここにいるよ　見つけてくれたから
I'm here, because you found me
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ　みんなで歌おう
I came here because I wanted to see you, let's all sing together
終わらないメロディ
An unending melody
キラメキに乗って
Ride on the sparkle
イェーイ！
Yeah!
AZKi先輩本当におめでとう！
AZKi-senpai, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
あー幸せな誕生日だー
Ah, such a happy birthday.
これからもよろしくねー！
Let's keep getting along!
よろしくねー、よろしくねー！
Let's get along, let's get along!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
超生誕祭2021
コラボ3D LIVE!!
Super Birthday 2021
Collab 3D LIVE!!
ピンポンパンポーン
Ding-dong-dang-dong
本日は、AZKi超生誕祭2021をご覧いただき、ありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching AZKi Super Birthday 2021 today!
ぜひ感想は、#AZKi超生誕祭2021でつぶやいてください。
Please tweet your thoughts using #AZKiChouSeitansai2021.
一つ一つ大切に読みに行きます。
I'll go and read each and every one carefully.
ということで、ねねちとわため、ありがとう！
And so, Nenechi and Watame, thank you!
こちらこそありがとうございましたー！
Thank you as well!
めちゃくちゃめちゃくちゃ幸せな生誕祭になりました。
It was an incredibly, incredibly happy birthday celebration.
楽しかったー！
It was fun!
楽しかった！普通に、普通に楽しい、あの、オタクをして...
It was fun! Just normally, normally fun, uh, being an otaku...
オタクをしながら一緒に歌えるという、これ以上ない喜びを。
Singing together while being an otaku, it's the greatest joy.
最高の時間だったねー！
It was the best time!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
また、また一緒に何か歌ったり、ライブしたりできる日を楽しみに待っております。
I'm looking forward to the day we can sing or perform together again.
こちらこそ！頑張ります！
Likewise! We'll do our best!
はい、それではじゃあ、みんなでバイバイで締めたいと思います。
Okay, then, let's finish with everyone saying bye-bye.
それではじゃあ...
Well then...
バイバイ！バイバイ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
〇〇初お披露目！？ 重大発表！？
?? First Reveal!? Major Announcement!?
コラボ3D LIVE!! 超生誕祭2021
Collaboration 3D LIVE!! Super Birthday Festival 2021